# **Karly Sindy**

765 Shell Sand Circle Charleston, SC 29412

karlysindy@gmail.com 919-218-0019 www.linkedin.com/in/ksindy https://github.com/ksindy

I can develop multi-functional websites including database integration using LAMP stack. I transitioned to this field when I saw a need for automated analysis that was not being met. My website now saves time and money for several academic labs. I have worked both in academic research and the medical device industry.

### **Technical Skills**

My capabilities are proven in the following areas:

Languages: Python, R, CSS, HTML, Bash

Technologies: Linux, MySQL, Django, Docker, Jupyter Notebooks, GitHub, Adobe Photoshop

### Education

Master of Science in Molecular Biology/Biotechnology, East Carolina University, Greenville, NC- May 2009 Bachelor of Science in Biological Sciences, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC- May 2007

## **Professional Training**

Python for Bioinformatics, University of Colorado Denver- May 2015 Eukaryotic Genome Annotation Course, J Craig Venter Institute, Rockville, MD- September 2009

### **Professional Experience**

University of Colorado Denver- February 2012 - August 2016

Worked with a team of scientists researching the epigenetic formation and regulation of chromatin.

- I wrote python code to perform high throughput analysis on millions sequencing reads to discover significant genomic areas of interest.
- I planned and performed experiments to discover the mechanism of long non-coding RNA's involvement in chromatin silencing.
- Publication: Meredith EK, Balas MM, Sindy K, Haislop K, Johnson AM2. An RNA matchmaker protein regulates the activity of the long noncoding RNA HOTAIR. 2016. RNA 22(7):995-1010.

Allosource- February 2011-February 2012

Worked with the Stem Cell group of the R&D team at AlloSource.

- Completed seven research and development projects. This process included independently designing
  and performing studies that directly affected product process changes and writing approved SOP
  reports. During this process, I have implemented new techniques and assays to the lab such as:
  zymogram gels, IF-IHC, and metabolic cell count assays.
- Worked with third party companies in order to transition two product processes for validation.

National Jewish Health July 2010- February 2011

Participated in research related to Immunology

• Independently conduct experiments related to Staphylococcal Infections.

 Treat HaCat, primary human keratinocyte cells with Staphylococcal toxins and extract protein and RNA and make cDNA followed by qPCR, western blot, cell death assays and plaque assays.

Syngenta- January 2010-July 2010

Member of vector construction team.

- Independently designed and performed an experiment comparing the efficiency of 12 different competent cell lines for use company wide.
- Perform restriction digests, DNA isolation, ligation, transformation and related cloning procedures for use in a high throughput vector construction team.

East Carolina University- Department of Biology, Greenville, NC Completed a research based masters thesis.

August 2007-May 2009

- Microinjected genetically modified adenoviral constructs to target the over-expression of two domains of the versican molecule in the developing chick limb in order to better understand the role of a proteoglycan in osteogenesis. Utilized my skills in PCR, immunohistochemistry, adenoviral biology, mammalian cell culture and microinjections.
- Publication: Hudson, K.S., Andrews, K.A., Early, J.K., and T.T. Capehart. Overexpression of the G1
  Domain and V3 Isoform of Versican During Chick Limb Development In Ovo. 2010. Anatomical Record
  293(10):1669-1678.

## Academic Honors, Awards, and Affiliations

Presidential Management Fellowship Nominee, Spring 2009
Recipient of James McDaniel Scholarship, 2008-2009, Department of Biology, East Carolina University
Mentor for Emerging Leaders Program Fall, 2008, East Carolina University
Member of Emerging Leaders Program Spring 2008, East Carolina University
Dean's List Fall 2002-Spring 2007, North Carolina State University
University Scholars Program, North Carolina University

## **Volunteer and Enrichment Activities**

Yoga Instructor, Denver, CO January 2012-2015
Raptor Handler, Hawk Quest, Parker, CO 2013-2015
Animal Assisted Therapy Volunteer, November 2011- 2013
Transplantation Sciences Education Team Member, Centennial, CO 2011
Reading Buddy at Kunsberg School, Denver, CO 2010
Intramural Soccer 2008-2009